Obinna Nnenanya

Data Engineer At Namely

7 Abike Shokunbi, Itamaga, Ikorodu, Lagos +234 (803) 622-3826 obinnaeye@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Namely, New York City - USA, — Data Engineer

(Andela's partnering company)

March 2018 - PRESENT

Building Data pipelines, ETL processes, Data analysis, Data query optimization, Building Data schemas, Creation of design docs, Code reviews, Data workflow.

Mozilla, San Francisco - USA — Backend Developer

(Andela's partnering company)

July 2017 - October 2017

Worked on Mozilla's internal release software (Balrog) where I built API endpoints that are utilized by the client-side for historical data analysis and point-in-time data representation.

Andela, Lagos - Nigeria — Software Developer

April 2017 - Present

Work effectively with design teams to ensure software solutions elevate client-side experience, Modify existing software to fix bugs, upgrade interfaces and improve performance, build elegant web and mobile apps.

Kings Home Tutors, Anambra — Technical Director/Owner

January 2011 - Present

Develop curriculums for tech classes, Network administration, Software maintenance, Business report and analysis, HR executive.

EDUCATION

National Open University, Nigeria — *PGDE Education*

January 2013 - December 2013

Nnamdi Azikiwe University, Nigeria — B.Sc Biochemistry

January 2003 - August 2007

Class Rep 2006, Students' Academic Director 2005, Final Year Coordinator 2007.

SUMMARY

I have ample experience in software development with interests in web and mobile applications, project management and data engineering. I am also passionate about code mentoring; grooming students into world-class developers. I believe in excellence, passion, integrity and collaboration.

SKILLS

Agile Methodologies, Version Control, Project Management, Communication, Remote teamwork, Database management, Data analysis, Mobile app development (React Native), Online coaching/mentorship, TDD.

STACKS

Python,
Javascript,
SQL,
React, Django and Flask,
REST Api,
D3js,
Nodejs,
Mongo DB,
Git,
Looker,

Apache Airflow,

Agulue Grammar School, Agulu, Nigeria — SSCE

August 1996 - June 2002

Deputy Senior Prefect, President - Anglican Students Association of Nigeria.

PROJECTS

WeVote — Citizen Mobilisation App

http://wevote-ng.herokuapp.com/

Force Directed Graph of State Contiguity

Data Visualisation with D3

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/JbLvVJ/

Video Streaming with Twitch

Web crawling

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/EypJBy/

Global Meteorite Landings

Data Visualisation with D3

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/PbBWmM/

Doping in Professional Bicycle Racing

Data Visualisation with D3

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/PbErBQ/

Monthly Global Land-Surface Temperature

Data Visualisation with D3

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/XNZpZL/

Game of Life

Effects of overcrowding vs loneliness on life

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/xEJzao/

Tic-Tac-Toe Game

Algorithm Exercise

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/ozjWgV/

Digital Calculator

Application of Javascript in general sciences

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/Vjoqzj/

Simon Game

Memory exercise

https://codepen.io/obinnaeye/full/mAPxjW/

AWARDS

Saucecode Pioneer Winners

Team WeVote: We built a citizen mobilisation app for

Nigerian elections.

http://wevote-ng.herokuapp.com/

LANGUAGES

Igbo, English, Hausa

HOBBIES

Playing guitar (Bass guitar) Playing table tennis Learning new stuffs Talking to young people

LINKS

https://about.me/nnenanya, https://ng.linkedin.com/in/ki ngobi, https://github.com/obinnaeye